NILTON CESAR ROJAS VALES

DETAILS

ADDRESS

Virgen del Carmen - Mz X Lote 3, Jose Marti Avenue Lima, Lima 10 Perù

PHONE

971824177

EMAIL

nrojasv@uni.pe - DNI: 73901142

DATE / PLACE OF BIRTH

07-03-1996 El Agustino

NATIONALITY

Peruana

LINKS

Github:

https://github.com/Nicerova7

<u>Linkedin: Nilton Cesar</u> Rojas Vales

LANGUAGES

English at the British Peruvian Cultural Association

....

SKILLS

Creatividad

Rápido en aprender

Machine Learning

Buena comunicación

Altamente motivado

Habilidades computacionales altas

Capacidad para trabajar en equipo

PROFILE

Bachelor of Computer Science from the National University of Engineering. High experience in Python and Typescript. Advanced database level Postgresql, Mysql and MongoDB. Experience with AWS creating S3 buckets and lambda functions. Trained to develop statistical models, carry out Machine Learning algorithms and Neural Networks in Python. Experienced using data libraries like pandas, numpy and scikit-learn and visualization libraries like matplotlib and seaborn. Experience as a software developer and as a Data Analyst.

EDUCATION

Bachiller, Universidad Nacional de Ingeniería

Lima

Aug 2014 - May 2019

I got the first place in the Computer Science program at admission university test. Top 20% of my faculty in nine of ten academic terms and top 33% in the remaining academic term.

I did my graduation thesis on recurrent neural network oriented to the Lima Stock Exchange using official data from the Lima Stock Exchange and I participate with this project in the exhibition to achieve the accreditation of Computer Science program in my university by the accreditation Board for Engineering and Technology (ABET).

INTERNSHIPS

Pasante de Inteligencia artificial, Wisy, Inc

Sep 2020 - Dec 2020

Internship in artificial intelligence developing Deep learning models for computer vision at Wisy, based at 156 2nd Street, San Francisco, CA 94105, in acceleration with Google.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Machine Learning Engineer, RappiPay Colombia

Jun 2022 - Present

Developing and analyzing Machine Learning models: Customer behavior, delinquent customer prevention, fraud prevention and propensity for new customers. Code Review for the Analytics area, main language SQL (Snowflake). Automation of processes involved in data modeling.

Data Analyst & Analytics, Culqi S.A.C

Oct 2021 - Apr 2022

Development of ETLs (Python, mongodb and postgresql) and data extraction with complex postgresql queries for power BI reporting, Process automation with Python.

Software Developer, Culqi S.A.C

Mar 2020 - Oct 2021

Creation, maintenance and refactoring of microservices and orchestrators in moderately complex systems, using unit testing and Agile methodology.

COURSES

Machine Learning, Modelos y Principios de Simulación, MIT xPRO

Feb 2022 - Mar 2022

Machine Learning with Python-From Linear Models to Deep Learning, MITx

Feb 2021 — Jun 2021

Probability - The Science of Uncertainty and Data, MITx

Feb 2020 — May 2020

Machine Learning: Data Science en Python, Udemy

May 2021 - Jul 2021